<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pictures on internet weblog</title>
    <link>https://juandpinto.com/tags/pictures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pictures on internet weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 21:07:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://juandpinto.com/tags/pictures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrapping-up Petra</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 21:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</guid>
      <description>In only a few hours I am to get on a plane and begin the next phase of my adventures this summer. The last six weeks have blown by much faster than I can believe. But, c&amp;rsquo;est la vie I suppose.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really have much to say at this point, though maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just because I&amp;rsquo;m so tired. We spent the day driving to Amman and relaxing in our hotel rooms, but though my body is exhausted, my mind is too excited to sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petra, wonder of the world</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/petra-wonder-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 20:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/petra-wonder-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>It is absolutely unbelievable that I&amp;rsquo;m actually in this place. Not only that I’m here, but that I’m doing what I’m here to do.
I came to Petra for the first time almost two years ago as part of the BYU Jerusalem Center study abroad. I remember the preparation we received prior to our Jordan trip, and how we were told that we would want to see as much of Petra as we possibly could during our single day here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris is always a good idea</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/paris-is-always-a-good-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 18:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/paris-is-always-a-good-idea/</guid>
      <description>I never quite realized how much hard work a dedicated blogger must put into his or her posts and photos. This is especially true when traveling in areas where free internet is hard to come by. For me it has meant, more than anything, lack of sleep. Such as right now when I am up in my hotel room in Amman, running on my minimal sleep from the last few days, and unwilling to go to bed until at least something is published.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>