<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>@Juan Pinto’s internet weblog - internet weblog</title>
    <link>https://juandpinto.com/https://juandpinto.com/</link>
    <description>All entries in internet weblog on internet weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 13:34:06 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-12-09-having-great-success/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 13:34:06 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-12-09-having-great-success/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having great success moving my old travel blog posts from WordPress to Jekyll. Still have a lot on the to-do list for my new site, but it’s nice to see some progress once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-12-07-reminiscing-on-a/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 07:28:26 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-12-07-reminiscing-on-a/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/43bdf93d90.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/43bdf93d90.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; style=&#34;display: inline-block; max-height: 200px; width: auto; padding: 1px;&#34; class=&#34;sunlit_image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/7d37014c76.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/7d37014c76.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; style=&#34;display: inline-block; max-height: 200px; width: auto; padding: 1px;&#34; class=&#34;sunlit_image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/2658ba4680.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/2658ba4680.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; style=&#34;display: inline-block; max-height: 200px; width: auto; padding: 1px;&#34; class=&#34;sunlit_image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/019b060b3f.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/019b060b3f.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; style=&#34;display: inline-block; max-height: 200px; width: auto; padding: 1px;&#34; class=&#34;sunlit_image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reminiscing on a great last week of Fulbright training in Jordan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Jordan training and thoughts on education</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jordan-training-and-thoughts-on-education/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jordan-training-and-thoughts-on-education/</guid>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://juandpinto.com/images/2018-12-06_01.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://juandpinto.com/images/2018-12-06_01.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I spent most of last week at a Fulbright training in Amman, Jordan. All the Fulbright English Teaching Assistants from the entire MENA region (Middle East, North Africa) were brought there for an intense few days of training on language acquisition theories, teaching techniques, and lesson planning. And intense it was!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://juandpinto.com/images/2018-12-06_02.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://juandpinto.com/images/2018-12-06_02.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We had three entire days of trainings, discussions, workshops, and even mock classes that we planned and then presented to the rest of the group. At times I felt like a schoolchild again, sitting all day in class and listening to the teacher. But, despite the occasional desire to take a post-lunch nap, I found my time there to be really valuable both as a Fulbrighter and as an educator in the broader context. I gained some interesting insights on how I can improve my own teaching assignments. I also came away with a little more experience with planning and leading a lesson. My teaching partner and I led the rest in an English-for-work-purposes lesson on job interviews, and we received some valuable feedback from our peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the last day of the trip exploring the ruins of Jerash, which was a wonderful way to finish our adventure. Our tour guide provided some fascinating historical context to the city and also to the modern country of Jordan. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent some in Jordan in the past—touring, studying, and excavating. I always enjoy visiting. I even got to use some of my rusty Arabic and felt a renewed desire to work on it some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://juandpinto.com/images/2018-12-06_03.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://juandpinto.com/images/2018-12-06_03.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My biggest takeaway, though, came from hearing about everyone&amp;rsquo;s different teaching conditions. Perhaps the most surprising thing for me was to hear of classes with &lt;em&gt;over one hundred students&lt;/em&gt;. A class that big is bad enough for lecture-style courses on biology or American history; for a language class, that size is absurd. Honestly, how are students supposed to learn English when sitting on long rows of benches with so many other students and one teacher in the front? Languages are learned through interaction and use, not from taking notes on what the teacher says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, not all of my colleagues are in situations like these. And I have no doubt that all my fellow Fulbrighters are doing a wonderful job teaching their students. But more than anything, hearing about this made me sad. I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with the salaries or reputation of teachers in other countries, but in the United States the teaching profession is not as highly esteemed as it should be. Teachers are expected to infuse future generations with the knowledge, character, and qualities they need to be fully-capable, contributing members of society. They&amp;rsquo;re often confronted with difficult situations like bullying, students with learning disabilities, and all sorts of flak from kids who are just barely beginning to find their place in the world. And most of them do this terribly difficult, demanding, and supremely important job while receiving little monetary compensation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? How about instead of spending obscene amounts of tax dollars on the military, on politicians&amp;rsquo; expensive tastes, or on a pointless wall, we instead wisen up and invest more on our kids&amp;rsquo; (and the world&amp;rsquo;s) future? Raising teacher wages, I propose, would simultaneously raise the competitiveness of getting a teacher job, the amount that future teachers choose to invest in their own education and training, their ability to perform under high-stress situations (due to better training and compensation), and the respect that they are given by the rest of the community. It simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me why the teaching profession so seldom receives the honor it deserves. My understanding is that teachers are respected much more in some other countries, but I have no experience with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://juandpinto.com/images/2018-12-06_04.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://juandpinto.com/images/2018-12-06_04.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that I need to learn more about the education systems that exist around the world. I want to better understand how we got to where we are, how much things have improved over the last decades and even centuries, and where we go from here. This is an area I should know more about, and one I commit myself to studying in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-12-03-stanford-and-upenn/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 16:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-12-03-stanford-and-upenn/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford and UPenn applications are in. Just one more to go. 🎓&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-29-spent-my-last/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 20:53:07 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-29-spent-my-last/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Spent my last day in Jordan exploring the ruins of Jerash, one of the ancient cities of the Roman Decapolis. And now, time to go home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/d90d748b9c.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/d90d748b9c.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-28-just-submitted-my/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 23:02:50 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-28-just-submitted-my/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just submitted my first application to a Ph.D. program. The other ones are just about complete at this point too, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of hitting submit. I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to slowly feel the application pressure lifting off my shoulders. Next up is the waiting game. 🎓&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Plan for site and blog</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/plan-for-site-and-blog/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 17:11:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/plan-for-site-and-blog/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;This site is very much a work in progress. I have many IndieWeb protocols I hope to implement in the near future, especially WebMentions. I also want to import many of my past ramblings from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.wordpress.com&#34;&gt;previous blog&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;last used in 2014!&lt;/em&gt;) and maybe even from Facebook and Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I think it important to give a basic overview of what I plan to do here. This post will address two questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is this site organized?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will I blog about?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-is-this-site-organized&#34;&gt;How is this site organized?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan is to have this site organized into three main areas: academic information, blog, and microblog. Academic information includes things like my CV, current projects, data and code repositories, etc. This is my main reason for a having a site at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog and microblog sections are meant to replace my dependence on social media silos such as Facebook and Twitter. Though I still plan to syndicate anything I do here to those and other platforms, my posts and thoughts will reside on my own site first and foremost.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:microblog&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:microblog&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The blog section is for longer articles, while my microblog is (theoretically) restricted to shorter posts, pictures, and check-ins—think Twitter or short Facebook posts. My reason for separating these into two separate sections is to make it easier to find an organized set of more though-out articles in the midst of a flood of short posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least this is how I plan to have things organized for now. All of it is subject to change in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-will-i-blog-about&#34;&gt;What will I blog about?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great question. Seeing as my life consists of two main areas, everything I post will fall into one or the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost is my family life. I really hit the jackpot on this one. I have the most wonderful wife and children I could ask for, and they are by far the best aspect of my life. I&amp;rsquo;ve only been married for three and a half years, but we&amp;rsquo;ve already had some crazy adventures as a family. In fact, we&amp;rsquo;re spending this academic year in Israel, so you can bet I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting a bit about our time here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my posts in this category will be delegated to my microblog. I think this arrangement makes sense since it&amp;rsquo;ll mostly be small, independent events that I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing from my personal and family life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I&amp;rsquo;m not sure yet, I expect that most of my longer blog posts will deal with topics related to my professional interests. This could include insights on language acquisition, news on educational technology, use-cases for learning analytics or data science techniques, and open science. I&amp;rsquo;ll also post about hobbies and non-professional interests like the IndieWeb, my own site, books I&amp;rsquo;m reading, travel, and politics. But posts about more personal aspects of my life will probably surface occasionally as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s it. This post is mainly an attempt to get me motivated to post regularly and to make me more accountable. I hope to revisit these questions in a few months and see where things are at then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:microblog&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m relying entirely on &lt;a href=&#34;https://micro.blog&#34;&gt;Micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; for the hosting and implementation of my microblog. I&amp;rsquo;d prefer to not have this be a permanent arrangement, but it&amp;rsquo;s working nicely for now.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:microblog&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-27-break-time-in/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 13:56:22 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-27-break-time-in/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Break time in Amman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/80b6f5a6b0.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/80b6f5a6b0.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-26-exhausted-from-a/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 21:59:04 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-26-exhausted-from-a/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Exhausted from a day of TESOL trainings and lots of food in Amman, Jordan. Not looking forward to a long night of fine-tuning my Ph.D. program applications and grading some papers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-24-rescued-an-adorable/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 16:55:26 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-24-rescued-an-adorable/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rescued an adorable kitten today that was stuck in a tree. Good deed for the day: complete ✅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/09e3d289e9.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://microblog.juandpinto.com/uploads/2018/09e3d289e9.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Motivation for renewed blog</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/motivation-for-renewed-blog/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/motivation-for-renewed-blog/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve  been thinking a lot lately about the internet presence I wish to create for myself. With all of this year&amp;rsquo;s revelations on Facebook&amp;rsquo;s serious data mismanagement (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook–Cambridge_Analytica_data_scandal&#34;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt;), political interference (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/17/technology/indictment-russian-tech-facebook.html?module=inline&#34;&gt;Russian hackers&lt;/a&gt;), failure to control hate speech (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/myanmar-facebook-hate/&#34;&gt;Myanmar genocide&lt;/a&gt;), and—most recently—dishonest efforts to shift blame (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/technology/facebook-data-russia-election-racism.html&#34;&gt;oh boy, where to begin&lt;/a&gt;), the backlash against social media platforms as a whole has reached fever pitch. It has caused me to reflect on my own contributions to the direction the web takes and our legacy for future generations of internauts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a self-described advocate of open science, open data, open educational resources, and open-source software, it comes as no surprise that I am also a big fan of the open web. The so-called &amp;ldquo;walled gardens&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:gardens&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:gardens&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that have taken over the web—those same ones that sell their users and their data for a quick buck—clearly don&amp;rsquo;t have our best interest in mind. How could they? By design, their business model is incompatible with the idea of the open web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet made it possible to connect to a highway of information. The World Wide Web ensured that this highway would be free from interference by powerful entities bent on controlling the on and off ramps to this highway, the direction that traffic would flow, and the toll stations that would have been placed along the way. Some early forces tried to become the guardians of the internet—they wanted to make the highways smooth and the landscape scenic, but with the understanding that they were in charge. Instead, the web was a lawless land of opportunity. It often led to potholes and dead ends, but it made every car, bicycle, and pedestrian on the highway a free traveler. Most importantly, it made it possible for any traveler to build a home along this highway that anyone could visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But over the last decade, things have changed. The rise of social media has made personal sites and blogs a rare sight. Instead, people flocked to these neatly-trimmed &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; spaces to post about their lives and connect with friends. Why? Two reasons: (1) the &amp;ldquo;everyone&amp;rsquo;s here&amp;rdquo; mentality and (2) convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, people have begun to realize that this convenience comes at a hefty price. A handful of monopolies have become the de-facto rulers of the road. These corporations gather more data about more people than has ever been possible, the ownership of which their users sign away unwittingly through endless pages of legalese under the heading, &amp;ldquo;Terms and Conditions.&amp;rdquo; Contrary to what these platforms want you to think, your data is an extremely valuable currency. The more the internet grows, the more that one&amp;rsquo;s online identity grows in importance. Unfortunately, for many people now, Facebook &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve become enthralled by the idea of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org&#34;&gt;IndieWeb&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an effort that a group of techies have undertaken to make it just as easy and convenient to create an online social presence &lt;em&gt;on your own domain&lt;/em&gt; as on Facebook or Twitter. This means that everything you put up remains yours and yours alone. You control what goes up and what comes down. You decide who you wish to connect with and in what way. And best of all, when these big platforms fail—because they all eventually do—there&amp;rsquo;s no need to scramble to find the next big thing and start all over again. Everything is on your own domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that&amp;rsquo;s my motivation for this blog. &lt;strong&gt;But what am I going to blog about?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing as this initial post is getting to a bit long-winded, that&amp;rsquo;ll be the topic of my next post. I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a plan for the blog and for this site as a whole. I&amp;rsquo;ll also discuss how I&amp;rsquo;ve organized different parts of the site, some of the technology behind it, and why I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen what I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:gardens&#34;&gt;Or &amp;ldquo;walled factories,&amp;rdquo; as Alan Jacobs so lovingly calls them in his fantastic essay, &lt;a href=&#34;https://iasc-culture.org/THR/THR_article_2018_Spring_Jacobs.php&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tending the Digital Commons: A Small Ethics toward the Future&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:gardens&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-23-our-baby-girl/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 13:07:57 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-23-our-baby-girl/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our baby girl sure had a happy Thanksgiving with good friends in Haifa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.micro.blog/uploads/2018/3f5a78f860.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.micro.blog/uploads/2018/3f5a78f860.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-20-personal-site-is/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 14:02:17 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/microblog/2018-11-20-personal-site-is/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Personal site is slowly, but surely, coming together. Meanwhile, Ph.D. applications keep kicking my trash.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Bigotry and fear: The chicken and the egg</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/bigotry-and-fear/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/bigotry-and-fear/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, the world has seemed caught in the intoxicating mentality of &lt;em&gt;us versus them&lt;/em&gt;. There’s nothing new about this. Yet the ongoing Syrian refugee crisis has proven a worthy litmus test for the way we experience life. Are these people victims of tragedy or Islamic instigators of terrorism? Do we aid the oppressed or protect our children?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Twain once suggested that “travel is fatal to prejudice, bigotry, and narrow-mindedness.”￼ Yes, my dear man, well said. The cure to xenophobia is to see the world—to leave the motherland, to learn a foreign language, or at the very least to become acquainted with “them.” Or is there more to it all? Certainly there are those who pass and surpass this short list of requirements and yet flunk the test of brotherly love. What is it that really makes the difference? How does one come to see the “other” as a fellow member of the human family?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the answer, fear seems to stand in stark contrast to this goal. But is fear the &lt;em&gt;cause&lt;/em&gt; of bigotry or merely its offspring? Chicken or the egg? When confronted with a fear of the “other,” our immediate reaction should be self-reflection. But how can anyone honestly step back and reflect on the root of that fear once it’s found a place in the heart? I think of caring, good, honest people I know—who would not hesitate to help a stranger in need—but who, when confronted with the dark mist of fear, become protective, make unkind generalizations, and may even act in a way that would shame them if they could but step out of themselves for one moment. Are we not all at risk of this fear? Are we not all guilty of it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, where does one draw the line? At what point does fear become justified, urgent, life-saving? Preventing terrorist attacks is a worthy cause—one worth fighting for. But again, where is the line? Do the ends justify the means? Never? Sometimes? What about now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is awfully smaller than it once was, and I assure you, this is no baseless cliché. What affects people of distant lands can have very real—and often very quick—repercussions in the lives of strangers across the world. So why do we keep pretending like it’s us versus them? This illusion is precisely the opposite of the truth of the human family. It’s a lie born of fear and simultaneously the mother of fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fear has been feeding our political campaigns. What I find most disturbing about Trump isn’t his complete lack of common sense, his pandering to the masses (of idiots), or even his proposed policies that are nothing but racism and hate. It’s his slogan. To be sure, the desire to improve this wonderful Union of States is an admirable goal. What disgust me aren’t the words that make up Trump’s slogan—rather, it’s the narcissistic cancer that comes attached to those words. If his policies were truly aimed at improving life, his slogan really would mean “make America great again.” But this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; what’s implied by suggestions of Muslim registry lists and informants in mosques. Or by the cheers and oblations offered up by rally-goers as they beat Blacks who “should have been roughed up,” ￼ scoff at Latinos, and banish veiled women. Or by campaign ads that depict misidentified “Mexicans” running en masse toward a promised wall of hate.￼ It’s also &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; what’s implied by all the talk of carpet-bombing civilians in a distant land where all men, women, and children are surely filthy terrorists. What all this implies is that “making America great again” isn’t about making America great at all. It’s about acting as if only America matters. “God bless America, and no one else.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump isn’t directly to blame for this cancer. If anything, he’s more like the diagnostic test that’s made possible a terrible discovery: the malignant tumor has long metathesized. And yes, it has even reached some critical organs. It’s too late for chemo, doc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Twain’s statement is true, not universally and not because of some intrinsic elixir granted by simply seeing the world. It’s true because of what it says about humanity. As with Trump’s slogan, the words themselves don’t carry the quote’s true meaning, its context does. The words that follow Twain’s quote: “Broad, wholesome, charitable views of men and things cannot be acquired by vegetating in one little corner of the earth all one&amp;rsquo;s lifetime.” I interpret this cure not as travel in the sense of physical movement, but in the sense of not vegetating—of seeing the world with global eyes. Universal eyes aren’t blind to color, as some may believe—they see differences in culture, they taste it, smell it, hear it. But they also see humanity for what it is: a family of individuals with different backgrounds but the same hopes, trials, dreams, and letdowns—the same life as you and me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, even racists and close-minded fools are part of this family of ours. And, very much like them, I too am guilty of judging my “other” to be of little worth. Does that not make me a hypocrite? I see Trump’s followers with the same distrustful, fearful eyes with which they see much of the world. I don’t expect to ever agree with them, but why is it so easy to exclude them all from my own human family? Suddenly, “stepping back” and seeing my own fear for what it is becomes nearly impossible. After all, I’m right and they’re wrong. &lt;em&gt;It’s me versus them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Stowaway Magazine: Petra&#39;s Hidden Treasures</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/stowaway-magazine-petras-hidden-treasures/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/stowaway-magazine-petras-hidden-treasures/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was interviewed by the great &lt;a href=&#34;http://nataliecherie.weebly.com&#34;&gt;Natalie Campbell&lt;/a&gt; for this wonderful article published on Stowaway Magazine. It describes some of the highlights of my time excavating in Petra last summer. Natalie also does a good job capturing a snapshot of what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be a student archaeologist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A bittersweet farewell</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/a-bittersweet-farewell/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 21:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/a-bittersweet-farewell/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;Now that my Cambridge experience has come to an end, it&amp;rsquo;s time to reflect on my two months spent there. But first, a quick recap of my adventures of the last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;northern-england&#34;&gt;Northern England&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent Tuesday through Thursday morning way up north. Some future in-laws have been living up there for the last two years, and they welcomed me with open arms. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to expect—not being familiar with the towns and sights to see up there—but wanted to go up anyway to spend time with them. I was blown away by everything I got to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right from the get-go we started driving to some of the places they thought I&amp;rsquo;d enjoy. We went to York that first day, where I climbed a fortress and an ancient city wall, walked through what is essentially a real-life Diagon Alley, enjoyed some classic fish-n-chips, and visited the incredible York Minster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0018.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0018.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;So . . . where do I get my wand?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0024.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0024.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The magnificent York Minster.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0235.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0235.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Atop Malham Cove.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0120.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0120.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The next day we visited Howarth (known for its association with the Brontë Sisters), some beautiful abbey ruins, and the spectacular dales. The dales made me feel like I was trekking through the Shire. All it was missing was a hobbit house built into a hill, and maybe a pipe-smoking wizard arriving in time for some fireworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My adventures in the north ended up being a great time to spend my last week in the UK. I loved getting to know both the area and my hosts a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0150.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0150.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ancient rock walls on an ancient landscape.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0313.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0313.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Me with my amazing hosts.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0163.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0163.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;formal-and-farewell&#34;&gt;Formal and Farewell&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thursday I returned to Cambridge we had our last formal hall. We got together for some big group pictures beforehand, and then enjoyed a wonderful dinner with friends. All of that was followed by a night full of some surprisingly fun dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_03321.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_03321.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Say whaaat?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0369.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0369.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Last chance to be fancy!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The next day was my last full day there, so I clearly had to take advantage of it. I got up early enough to see the sunrise, which was beautiful. Unfortunately, the clouds and rain hampered the scene a bit, and made it impossible to take the picture of King&amp;rsquo;s College Chapel I was hoping for. This was all despite my favorable position on a certain part of the college that is &amp;hellip; well, let&amp;rsquo;s just say off-limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last night consisted of an unofficial party on the college grounds, where we ate lots of junk food, did a little bit of dancing, and played some games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0004.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0004.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our last game: catching whipped cream.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;thoughts-on-cambridge&#34;&gt;Thoughts on Cambridge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No doubt Cambridge has won a very special place in my heart. Before this summer, it seemed to me like one of those far-off places that only exists for impossibly brilliant scholars with ambitions to take over the world. Now it is a gathering-place for people from all around the globe who want nothing more than to make a difference and enjoy life while doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned so much while here—about myself and about others. I made some amazing friends that I am excited to visit in the near future. I saw parts of the world that I have only dreamed of. I have grown through experiences that have already shaped me for the better (hopefully). I have found another place that I can now call home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though my time at Cambridge has now come to a close, my summer adventures go on for one more week. I am now in Switzerland, hiking and biking through the magnificent Alps. Next up: more pictures of England and then a report on my time in this land of knives, cheese, chocolate, and watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0233.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0233.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The final stretch</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/the-final-stretch/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 22:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/the-final-stretch/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;With less than a week to go here at Cambridge, I’m definitely feeling the pressure to do some of the things I still haven’t gotten around to. That has so far meant a few days of traveling and visiting some of the most beautiful areas of Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also informed yesterday that I won the “Academic Life” category of the PKP Photo Competition! That does mean I get a prize, though I have yet to find out what it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0017.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0017.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The library at Pembroke College, Cambridge.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0125.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0125.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;PKP talent show!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0475.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0475.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Visiting chapels in Cambridge.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I had my last final exam on Friday, and since then I have been done with classes. The only school-related thing I have had to worry about is my supervision research paper. While I’ve certainly devoted a lot of time to getting that finished, I’ve also had more time to do other things than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day in London a week ago was a great success. I took the bus there with a group from PKP, and our program included watching a show at the Globe Theater—we saw Shakespeare’s &lt;em&gt;King Lear&lt;/em&gt;. And guess who played the part of King Lear? None other than Geoffrey the Butler from &lt;em&gt;Fresh Prince of Bel-Air&lt;/em&gt;. We went out afterwards and took great pictures of London at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the best part of the whole day was going to see &lt;em&gt;The Lion King&lt;/em&gt; broadway show! I’ve been wanting to see that show ever since I first heard about it in like elementary or middle school, no joke. Did it live up to my expectations? Absolutely. I enjoyed every minute of it, and ended up listening to the soundtrack non-stop for the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0114.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0114.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our happy faces after seeing the Lion King in London!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0149.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0149.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Waiting for our show to start at the Shakespeare Globe Theater.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_01821.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_01821.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Isn&amp;#39;t London beautiful at night?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-oxbridge-debate&#34;&gt;The Oxbridge Debate&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows about the (friendly?) rivalry between Cambridge and Oxford. Since I don’t know enough about the academics of one vs. the other, I can make no comment on that. But, since visiting Oxford this last Sunday, I can at least give my two cents on the differences I noticed and my own preferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to visit Oxford from the moment I arrived here, and I was certainly not disappointed. The weather while there at first didn’t seem ideal, but after the rain subsided and the sun came out, everything worked perfectly to our advantage. Oxford is beautiful. I mean it is stunning. I thought Cambridge was as beautiful as it could get, but Oxford’s grander buildings and gardens make it something else. The architecture is very similar, everything simply seemed to be at a bigger scale. At least to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0116.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0116.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Oxford University Library. Epic.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0285.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0285.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Stalker pic I got of some tennis players at Oxford.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0448.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0448.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Oxford stroll.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With that said, Oxford was in general a bigger city. The streets are much wider, there are many more cars and buses, and in general it has more of a city feel to it. Parts of it felt more like London than Cambridge. While that may be what some people prefer, this is one area where I enjoy Cambridge’s atmosphere better. Cambridge feels more like a small town where you grow up knowing everything and everyone (except the tourists) and where you can feel more like the town belongs to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing I wanted to do at Oxford was to visit the _Eagle and Child_ pub, where the Inklings used to meet. The Inklings was a group of friends that included the likes of J.R.R Tolkien and C.S. Lewis. At this very place, two entire worlds were created: Middle Earth and Narnia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_04392.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_04392.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Birthplace of Middle Earth and Narnia!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0444.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0444.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Random dude wearing the greatest shirt I&amp;#39;ve ever seen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0319.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0319.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We ran into some protesters at Oxford.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;adventures-still-to-come&#34;&gt;Adventures Still to Come&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since all I have to do now is finish revising my supervision paper, I’ve decided to go on one last adventure in England. This morning I took a train up north to Leeds, where I will be spending a couple of days at the house of some friends who will show me around the area. Thursday is our final goodbye formal, and Saturday I fly to my last destination this summer: Switzerland!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0525.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0525.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This is what my future house will look like. St. John&amp;#39;s College, Cambridge.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0578.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0578.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Home sweet home. King&amp;#39;s College, Cambridge.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It is very hard to believe how quickly this summer has flown by. At points it felt slow—to be sure—but now as I look back I realize that it really has been a surprisingly fast, action-filled &amp;hellip; break? Not much of a break perhaps, but certainly an experience to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not over yet. Stay tuned for what is sure to be a great end to this grand summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0590.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0590.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Yep, I really am that cool.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Cambridge and beyond</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/cambridge-and-beyond/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 21:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/cambridge-and-beyond/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;Wow, where to even begin? It&amp;rsquo;s now been just over a month since my last entry, which means I essentially have only two more weeks here at Cambridge. And believe me when I say that what an adventure it has been!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0002.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0002.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside King&amp;#39;s College, Cambridge. AKA home.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As a bit of background, our time here is split into two halves called &lt;em&gt;modules&lt;/em&gt;. My module 1 consisted of constant classes, readings, homework, and papers. This is because the entirety of one of my classes (Modern European History) was crammed into that single month, all while also having my two-month-long class (Good Life or Moral Life) and a Supervision research project. But despite all the craziness of that module, I survived, and with plenty to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0142.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0142.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Tour de France = day off from school.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;recent-adventures&#34;&gt;Recent Adventures&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekend between modules was a time to celebrate, and celebrate I did! Some friends and I decided we wanted to travel a bit, so after exploring countless options and nearly giving up, we found a great deal for bus tickets to &amp;hellip; drumroll &amp;hellip; Paris!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes sir, I returned to Paris to explore the parts of the city I missed last time and to enjoy it some more. We spent that Saturday in London and Sunday and Monday in Paris, traveling at night. That weekend, between the British Museum and the Louvre, I saw more famous artifacts from the ancient Near East than I had seen _ever_ before in my life. Loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0554.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0554.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Nothin&amp;#39; like a little solo salsa dancing on the streets of Paris.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0503.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0503.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Louvre, how I&amp;#39;ve missed thee.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0228.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0228.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Rosetta Stone at the British Museum. I finally made it through the mad crowd of people surrounding this beauty of a rock.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0347.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0347.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;London corner.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Other adventures here have included watching the &lt;em&gt;Tour de France&lt;/em&gt; come through Cambridge, being a tourist for the day and visiting museums and other colleges in town, going out with my camera to enjoy some beautiful views, punting down the River Cam, watching fireworks up close and personal from my front lawn, watching Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s _As You Like It _performed outside at the St. John&amp;rsquo;s College Gardens, going salsa dancing at the Cambridge University Social Club, singing hymns in the magnificent King&amp;rsquo;s College Chapel, and so so so much more. Not to mention adventures still to come, such as tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s trip to London to watch the Lion King performed at the Lyceum Theater, as well as a play at Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s Globe Theater later in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, everything here is so beautiful, that simply walking out in the morning, or sitting on my front lawn during sunsets are adventures in and of themselves. And turning corners to find hidden gems of open spaces full of gardens and old buildings makes me feel like I&amp;rsquo;m in Narnia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0137.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0137.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Don&amp;#39;t mind me, just enjoy this nice romantic ride down the river.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0064.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0064.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Fireworks. Because why not?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0391.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0391.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;didactic-ramblings&#34;&gt;Didactic Ramblings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how much I have learned here. Sure, I have learned plenty in my classes, especially Modern European History since it was a topic I hardly knew anything about but have since come to find fascinating. Still, most of what I&amp;rsquo;m learning is just simply from being here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0247.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0247.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside King&amp;#39;s College Chapel, the most iconic building at Cambridge.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most interesting of all is how every place I&amp;rsquo;ve visited during my adventures this summer has taught me different things about humanity, about myself, and about how I want to contribute to the world. Because of the very personal nature of many of the things I have learned, I don&amp;rsquo;t find this an appropriate place to talk about them. But I do want to emphasize just how important I now regard a wide education that is well-rounded and that pulls from all disciplines and from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve long been an advocate of broad liberal arts education, but more than ever do I understand how critical that is. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking strictly of formal education, but education in all its shapes. What I mean is that the books we read for pleasure, the things we look up on the internet, the way we spend our time—even the movies we watch—contribute to the way we perceive the world and what we can then offer in return. As Mark Twain once advised, &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t let schooling interfere with your education.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0063.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0063.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hidden garden at Peterhouse College, the oldest college at Cambridge.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;One last, unasked-for insight I want to share: playing hard is essential to working hard. Sure books are important, but so is going out to ride your bike, spending time chatting with friends, and my personal favorite—dancing the night away. Then when you do return to whatever kind of work your occupation entails—which here means reading reading reading—you will be that much better able to focus and enjoy what would otherwise be a monotonous task. That careful balance seems to be the mantra by which Cambridge students live. Plus, playing hard and working hard simply make me happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rambling over. For now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0573.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/dsc_0573.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Hogwarts</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/welcome-to-hogwarts/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 22:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/welcome-to-hogwarts/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My first week at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry has been a tremendous success. I&amp;rsquo;ve got the _wingardium leviosa _spell down pretty well, and have almost mastered the &lt;em&gt;expelliarmus&lt;/em&gt; spell. Next up: &lt;em&gt;avada kedavra&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in all seriousness. This place is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0014-2.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0014-2.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Feeling fancy at King&amp;#39;s Dining Hall.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0020.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0020.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Across the River Cam, King&amp;#39;s College.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My arrival at Cambridge—the town—was uneventful. I took the train from Stansted Airport and made it in about an hour. Getting to Cambridge—the university—was a different story altogether. For some odd reason, I was expecting to be received by a welcoming party at the train station for all Pembroke-King&amp;rsquo;s Programme (PKP) students. It sounds so foolish now, but I wholeheartedly believed it then. Clearly, it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I ended up walking from the train station in the direction that seemed most logical, and getting lost multiple times—in the pouring rain. Yep, luggage and all. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like wasting my money on a taxi; and really, how big could this town be anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that I did &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; find my way to King&amp;rsquo;s College, where I was joyfully greeted by friendly &amp;ldquo;porters&amp;rdquo; (the people in charge of letting people in or keeping them out). I was only completely soaked, and so were some of the clothes in my luggage. Since then things have been running much more smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0543.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0543.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Just outside King&amp;#39;s College.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;King&amp;rsquo;s College is where I chose to stay, and I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did, as it&amp;rsquo;s one of the most famous and beautiful colleges of the University of Cambridge. Everything here is pristine and ancient, the grounds are spectacular, the atmosphere is calm, the sunsets are brilliant, and the people are warm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0548.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0548.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;King&amp;#39;s College. I live here? What?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A few things that have surprised me about this place. For starters, the days are way longer than anything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced before. Apparently, we&amp;rsquo;re at roughly the same latitude as Alaska, which means that almost at 10:00pm it&amp;rsquo;s still fully bright outside, and by shortly after 4:00am the sun comes up. Also, it hadn&amp;rsquo;t occurred to me that Cambridge would be a very touristy town, but oh it sure is. Tourists fill the streets constantly and are always trying to get access to the inside of the college grounds. There are also about ten times as many bikes on the streets as cars, which I absolutely love. It all has a small-town but regal feel to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0072.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0072.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The evolution of man in front of Darwin College.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0141.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0141.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As for classes, I could not be more excited. I am taking two classes and doing something called &lt;em&gt;supervision&lt;/em&gt;. My classes are &amp;ldquo;Good Life or Moral Life&amp;rdquo; (ethics) and &amp;ldquo;Modern European History.&amp;rdquo; The supervision option is the opportunity to work one-on-one with a Cambridge professor or graduate student on a research topic of my choice. I&amp;rsquo;ve titled my research proposal &lt;em&gt;Divine Blood in the Mesopotamian Creation-of-Mankind Motif&lt;/em&gt;, and my supervisor is a current PhD candidate here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0247.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0247.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Celebrating the 4th of July atop Arthur&amp;#39;s Seat in Scotland.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_04511.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_04511.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Edinburgh.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0343.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0343.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Our first week has been rather unique, since we&amp;rsquo;ve just spent the last few days getting to know each other better in Edinburgh, Scotland. I had a great time there hiking, exploring the city, and dancing (and apparently also getting a little sick), but now we&amp;rsquo;re back and ready to start a full week of hard work. Well, at least after we go out to see the Tour de France go by here tomorrow. Look for me on TV!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0408.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0408.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Serious-ish faces with the guards of Edinburgh Castle.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0499.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0499.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Scottish dance night!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Jerusalem of gold</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jerusalem-of-gold/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 21:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jerusalem-of-gold/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My second week in Jerusalem was one heck of an adventure. For the most part, it was a continuation of the awesomeness that had been my first week. But in some ways, things were very different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0288.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0288.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Dome of the Rock and the Western Wall.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0271-2.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0271-2.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Worshippers at the Western Wall.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I decided that I needed to get out of the city at least once, so I chose to join a group from the hostel that was going down to the Judean Desert. Our trip began with a very early drive to Masada, a massive Herodian fortress built on top of a lone peak plateau overlooking the Dead Sea. We hiked up to the top and watched a spectacular sunrise from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking around and exploring the grounds for a bit, we hiked back down and drove through more desert to Ein Gedi. Ein Gedi is a nature reserve that consists of natural springs within the rocky mountains of the desert. It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful place where there is actually some green and wildlife, unlike the surrounding region. Some of us hung out and took a refreshing dip in the springs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0036.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0036.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunrise at Masada.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0098.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0098.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;View from the edge of Masada.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0187.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0187.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ein Gedi. Better believe I went swimming in those springs. They&amp;#39;re much bigger than they look.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Our last stop was the Dead Sea, where we floated in what always feels to me like oil, covered ourselves in rejuvenating Dead Sea mud, and sat around chatting. It was a good end to a great adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0204.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0204.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;El Mar Muerto. Or in Hebrew, Yam HaMelach (The Sea of Salt).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;What really made this second week different though was that I got to hang out so much with friends. A couple of friends from BYU came to do a summer Hebrew program at the Hebrew University, and I spent much of my free time with them and sometimes also with friends from the BYU Jerusalem Center. Because I was no longer on my own, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t forced to speak Hebrew all the time like before. But though it took some time away from my Hebrew experience, it was just too much fun hanging out with them. We had meals out in the town, played games with peeps at the Jerusalem Center, went to the Israel Museum, practiced some Hebrew, and just traveled around visiting sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0055.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0055.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Entering Hezekiah&amp;#39;s tunnel.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0195.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0195.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Tel Dan Stele! Oldest discovered mention of the House of David.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Overall I absolutely consider my time in Israel a success. The people at &lt;a href=&#34;http://ulpanor.com&#34;&gt;Ulpan Or&lt;/a&gt; were so much fun to work with, and they constantly pushed me to use my Hebrew and put myself out there. My primary goal was to become more comfortable having conversations on the street, and I can undoubtedly attest that that goal was met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0298.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0298.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jewish Quarter of the Old City.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0227.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0227.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jordan, Hannah, and Justin at the BYU Jerusalem Center.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now the next stage of my summer adventures has begun. I am writing this from my desk at Cambridge University, with a window in front of me overlooking the River Cam. More details on this exciting place to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0016.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/dsc_0016.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;King&amp;#39;s College, Cambridge University. My home for the next 8 weeks.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Journeys across the Mediterranean</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/journeys-across-the-mediterranean/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 18:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/journeys-across-the-mediterranean/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After practically living _in _Petra for a month and a half, intimately getting to know the sites daily and being constantly surrounded by 2,000 year-old buildings and inscriptions, I thought seeing Athens and then Jerusalem wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make much of an impact on me. Boy was I wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/2014-06-14-15-53-29.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/2014-06-14-15-53-29.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Excited? Better believe it.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My day in Athens was a blast. I essentially just had an 11-hour layover, which was the perfect amount of time to visit the Acropolis and then the Acropolis Museum. The city as a whole was beautiful and I found it easy enough to find my way around. The Acropolis itself was everything I expected and more. The architecture there blew me away, and it reminded me of my days touring Turkey. But it was really the museum that left me impressed far beyond what I expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0008.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0008.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;After climbing to Ad-Deir every day in Petra, this climb to the top of the Acropolis was child&amp;#39;s play in comparison.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0128.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0128.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The famous Parthenon.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0036.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0036.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Acropolis Museum is small compared to most others that house artifacts of such magnitude and importance, but the way things were organized, explained, and displayed, provided the perfect learning experience. I can safely say I learned much more about the ancient Greeks than I expected. And I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0175.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0175.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mmmm Greek food. Enjoying a relaxing date with me, myself, and I.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0040.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0040.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And now my first week in Jerusalem has been amazing. The first thing I did when I got here was of course to visit the Old City and many of my favorite spots. The smells, sights, and sounds brought back so many memories. But my favorite part of all has been speaking the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0233.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0233.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Old City of Jerusalem in the background.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I undoubtedly feel my Hebrew improving by leaps and bounds, especially when it comes to feeling comfortable having conversations on the street. I speak almost exclusively Hebrew all day, and it is making all the difference in the world. Learning a language is such a rewarding experience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0276.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0276.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Someone seriously needs to turn this into a superhero.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0269.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0269.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Nothing like going to the Festival of Lights in the Old City with old friends.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got one more week to go here, which I expect to be just as amazing (and even more &amp;hellip; check future posts) as the first. But for now, here I am, sitting in a hostel in Jerusalem, watching the Colombia vs. Ivory Coast game of the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vamos Colombia!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0280.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0280.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Wrapping-up Petra</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 21:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In only a few hours I am to get on a plane and begin the next phase of my adventures this summer. The last six weeks have blown by much faster than I can believe. But, c&amp;rsquo;est la vie I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really have much to say at this point, though maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just because I&amp;rsquo;m so tired. We spent the day driving to Amman and relaxing in our hotel rooms, but though my body is exhausted, my mind is too excited to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, this entire experience has been one long learning process. From learning about the technical aspects of archaeology, to finding out how much I love this place, to getting used to new peoples and customs, learning how to avoid getting frustrated while working hard in the sun, and learning how to work well in a team. Though I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on pursuing archaeology per se (I prefer different aspects of Ancient Near Eastern Studies), I have no doubt that my last few weeks here will shape much of my future life and career. I realized just how much I love this kind of work and its contributions to the areas I focus on. And again, I realized more than ever just how much I love the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, without further ramblings, here are just a few pictures from our most recent adventures. Stay tuned for everything soon to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=&amp;ldquo;rectangular&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;403,390,397,396,402,401,400,399,398,395,394,393,392,391,407&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;rand&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Ancient scrivenings, living tongues</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/ancient-scrivenings-living-tongues/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 22:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/ancient-scrivenings-living-tongues/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;I spent over half an hour yesterday speaking Hebrew with a native Israeli over Skype. It was an oral evaluation as part of the preparations for my two-week intensive ulpan which begins this coming Sunday! I had forgotten just how much I love that language until I got to listen to it again and speak it with surprising ease. I spent an hour after that just relaxing to Hebrew music and loving it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not only Hebrew, but the language aspect in general of my studies that I find myself most attracted to. This applies to whatever language pertains to wherever my current studies take me. While I’m here in the heartland of the Nabataean kingdom, that language is Nabataean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;!-- issue --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0014.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0014.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Some Nabataean left on the way up to Ad-Deir: shalem&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0592.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0592.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;An interesting carving on the way to Al Khazneh.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;nabataean-language&#34;&gt;Nabataean Language&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don’t wish to bore anyone with a full linguistic introduction, there are a few things I do want to explain. I’ll try to keep things simple and brief—something I often find hard to do. I can tell who my real friends are when they’ll happily sit through my non-sensical but excited ramblings out of duty instead of shared interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the few centuries spanning the rise of the Neo-Assyrian Empire until the fall of the Achaemenid Persian empire and the coming of the Greeks, the common language of the ancient Near East was Aramaic—a sister language to Hebrew and more distantly related to Arabic. This “Imperial Aramaic” spread throughout the whole region as the language of the elite and for inter-cultural communication. Eventually it trickled down to more common folk as a secondary language, though each area usually kept its own native tongue as well. This was somewhat similar to how English is used today throughout much of the world to communicate with foreigners, even when neither party comes from a natively English-speaking country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why certain late parts of the Old Testament are written in Aramaic instead of Hebrew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0307.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0307.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Nabataean graffiti can be found throughout the hidden passages of this rocky landscape.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the Nabataeans are believed to have been an Arabic-speaking tribe that migrated north from Arabia and settled in what today is Jordan and parts of southern Israel. Though it’s believed that they natively spoke an old form of Arabic, almost all their inscriptions and records are written in a modified late Aramaic. By this point (second and first centuries B.C.E.), some of the peoples in the Near East had modified Aramaic to their own needs and created dialects that combined it with their respective native languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in essence, the Nabataeans adopted Aramaic, modified the alphabet to be more cursive (much like the Syriacs did), and with time incorporated Arabic features into the language. This resulted in a distinctly Nabataean script and language for official use, different from the Nabataean form of Arabic they would have spoken in daily use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0291.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0291.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Something else that&amp;rsquo;s cool is that their script continued to be used and modified long after the end of the Nabataean kingdom, and eventually resulted in the classical Arabic script still in use today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pocket-change&#34;&gt;Pocket Change&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why does all this matter? Well first of all, it’s super cool. Secondly, because Aramaic is so closely related to Hebrew, I find it relatively easy to read. The script takes some getting used to, especially when n’s and b’s and l’s all look so similar, d’s and r’s are identical, and the writing in general looks rather messy, but with a little practice it’s gotten much easier and much more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But really, the reason I’m writing so much about this is because my primary responsibility here has become to deal with inscriptions. Not big inscriptions per say—since there are few and they have practically all been published already—but with the tiny inscriptions on the 60 or so coins we have found so far (and continue to find).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/img_0769.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/img_0769.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One of the many coins I must analyze and ideally date.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;While Skyping with my dad recently, he was very surprised that there is still so much out there to discover in the dirt. Well let me assure you, there is. Plenty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was assigned my responsibility with the coins precisely because of my interest in the Nabataean language. The director of our excavation at Ad-Deir saw this as a way to quench my thirst for inscriptions, and I’m very glad she did. I’ve now identified most of the coins and have learned much more about numismatics (just a fancy word that refers to the study of coins), Nabataean kingship, and ancient metallurgy than I could have learned otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- issue --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0147.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0147.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Laughing at Arabic graffiti that almost looks like Juan :) go.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;# Some Thoughts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have repeatedly mentioned in some of my previous posts, one of the aspects of archaeology and history I love most is the fact that we get to know a people distant by both space and time, but who lived, experienced joys and sorrows, and died, just like the rest of us. That’s also why I find language so fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language in itself is just a tool and means nothing—it has no intrinsic value. It’s only when language is used to communicate meaning, to record events, to share knowledge, ideas, experiences, feelings, beliefs, transactions, names, etc.—that it becomes something, not only useful, but beautiful. A language is always intimately intertwined and fused with the culture that uses it. Tolkien, a linguist, knew that very well, so he created an enormous world with believable cultures and detailed histories and vastly different people in order to make his languages have meaning. And it worked, unlike the countless languages that have been invented but without a people and history to make them real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0883.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0883.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Old Arabic alongside much more ancient designs.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So as with much else, that’s what studying the Nabataean language and script does for me: it helps me see the world through the eyes of a people long gone. Sure, coins don’t exactly have the most exciting inscriptions on them; believe me, I’ve stared at them enough to know that. But at the very least I get to see the names of their kings and queens in the language and script they would have heard and seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aretas the king, king of the Nabataeans, lover of his people”—in a way I can’t quite explain—carries much more meaning in the tongue of his people than it ever will in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0143.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/dsc_0143.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Of tombs and skeletons</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/of-tombs-and-skeletons/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 21:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/of-tombs-and-skeletons/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;This week I relocated from working at the temple on the mountaintop to the tomb in the valley. It&amp;rsquo;s my official transition to the second and last part of my adventure as an archaeologist this summer. Having been here for three of the six weeks meant it was time to rotate crews and excavation sites, so I am now working under a different site director in a very different place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday of last week was supposed to be my last day at Ad-Deir, so I knew I had to make it special. The climb up those steep, eroded steps usually takes about 30–40 minutes, but our site director claimed the record from last year to have been 18 minutes. Naturally, I set out to beat that record. At a “light” jog, I made it up and through the temenos wall in 12:57. I say “light” because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly fast, but the constant steep incline made it challenging. It was fun and exhausting. And Justin, thanks for encouraging me to jog with you this last semester. It was good conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0039.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0039.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our lower trench on the Ad-Deir Plateau.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0077.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0077.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our excavation trench at the great circle.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Sunday was the day of the rotation, but because two of the students in the other crew were sick and out of commission, I was asked to stay with the Ad-Deir group for one more day. So that meant Monday was when I got to begin my time at the tomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_00651.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_00651.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Saying goodbye to a fellow Bedouin worker at Ad-Deir.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-tomb&#34;&gt;The Tomb&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nabataean tombs are very filthy places. Well, at least today they are. These tombs have been used by various peoples and for various purposes since the Nabataeans abandoned Petra close to two thousand years ago. The Bedouin have used them for shelter and as stables for the last few hundred years, which is plenty of time for both human and animal waste to accumulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our tomb at Wadi Mataha, it takes digging well over a meter deep in old dung before getting to the floor the Nabataeans would have seen. Luckily, it’s been here long enough that the smell has _mostly_ gone away. Also luckily, we have Bedouin workers for hire to take out unwanted dung in the places we care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_08301.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_08301.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our tomb is the one on the right.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Most of these tombs have been broken into by looters looking for precious objects buried with the bodies. The previous archaeology group finished excavating a small loculus near the corner of the tomb, and were lucky enough to find part of a human skull still there. My group now gets to dig in a slightly larger loculus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0008.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0008.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our ingenious reflective lighting system at work. The Mummy, anyone?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the week we have taken turns digging through the southern part of the loculus and sifting all the dirt we pull out in our handy screen. It was only small animal bones and the occasional pottery sherd at first. That is, until we got down to our human skeleton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0014.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0014.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-skeleton&#34;&gt;The Skeleton&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to pull out the skull—a very unnerving experience considering the extremely fragile state of the bones. We have now removed the bones of the entire upper body and taken them to our lab for examination. Much of yesterday was spent identifying bones and teeth, particularly in order to assess the gender, age, and height of this Nabataean. I attempted to reconstruct the shattered scapula—one of the more complex and thin bones in the human body—and also got to help with identifying and measuring some other bones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.wordpress.com/summer-2014-goals/&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.wordpress.com/summer-2014-goals/&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Goal accomplished: Find a human skeleton in Petra.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_00381.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_00381.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;It&amp;#39;s all about working hard in uncomfortable positions.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_00642.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_00642.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bone analysis.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;ramblings&#34;&gt;Ramblings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that sometimes it’s easy to get so caught up in the data-driven aspect of archaeology, that I forget to reflect on the larger picture. These bones once belonged to a living, breathing human being, with goals, troubles, passions, fears, friends. Sure he lived in a very different time, with some very different customs and beliefs, but underneath it all, we share so very much in common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And after all, that’s what archaeology, anthropology, and history are really all about—about the human connection we all share that allows us to learn so much about ourselves by learning about others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0018.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0018.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Desert get-away</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/desert-get-away/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 18:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/desert-get-away/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever seen _Lawrence of Arabia_ then you know all about the incredible beauty that can be found in the deserts of the Arab world. One such beautiful place, Wadi Rum, was the location for most of the filming of the movie, and this weekend I got to hike and camp out in that very place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were told about the chance to go to Wadi Rum while we were still in the States, preparing for our trip, and of course I could not possibly pass up the chance of something like that. It did cost some extra money for our guide and accommodations, but it was worth every penny. Only a handful of us from the group chose to go on this adventure while the rest stayed at Umm Sayhoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0395.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0395.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;brief-history&#34;&gt;Brief History&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wadi Rum is the largest valley in Jordan. It lies east of Aqaba and is now primarily a tourist destination for backpackers, rock climbers, and travelers from all over the world. There is prehistoric graffiti in many of the rocks, serving as evidence of the ancient inhabitants of the land, as well as Thamudic inscriptions (an Old North Arabian dialect of the region), and some Nabataean inscriptions. The Nabataeans also left their mark with a beautiful temple, the remains of which can still be seen today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0169.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0169.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One of the many inscription-filled rocks in the wadi.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0110.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0110.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The famous &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The area is still mostly known for T. E. Lawrence’s part in the Arabian Revolt against the Turks. The capture of Aqaba—the first of Lawrence’s victories and the one that won him initial fame and trust—was staged and led from Wadi Rum. Some of the sites in the wadi have been named after Lawrence or his book, &lt;em&gt;Seven Pillars of Wisdom&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0307.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0307.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;weekend-adventure&#34;&gt;Weekend Adventure&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two-hour drive down from Petra on the ancient King’s Highway was a little rough because of all the wavy roads, but we made it in one piece and enjoyed some fantastic views on the way. The very first part of Wadi Rum that we saw at the entrance was the famous “Seven Pillars of Wisdom” rock, named after T. E. Lawrence’s book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we made it past the gate and into the small village in the park (where the Zalabia, the Bedouin tribe of that area, live), we got out of our van and jumped into the bed of a sweet safari-like Jeep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_01441.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_01441.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Most of our time was spent in that Jeep, cruising through sand dunes and checking out sweet rock formations, taking pictures, and overall just in awe of the vastness of the desert and the beauty around us. The breeze on the Jeep and the shade from our little canopy on the bed also helped keep us happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0179.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0179.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We climbed up some huge rocks to a patch of green around a natural spring, where we enjoyed the view and one of our team members took a water sample for her research project. We then had lunch and a little time to rest at our campsite at the foot of one of the giant rock formations. I took the chance any free moment I got to keep reading &lt;em&gt;Seven Pillars of Wisdom&lt;/em&gt;, which I have thoroughly enjoyed so far. We toured some more, watched the sunset on top of another rock formation, and made it back to the campsite for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0269.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0269.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Descending from our little spring in the desert.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_05982.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_05982.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Enjoying &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I feel like “rock formation” doesn’t do these giants justice. When I say they were giant, I really do mean massive, steep, rock mountains jutting out of the otherwise soft desert floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0624.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0624.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Getting ready for the sunset.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0673.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0673.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunset at Wadi Rum.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0716.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0716.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A couple of friends and I spent much of the night lying out under the stars, telling stories and our favorite ancient myths and epics. That’s what you do when you’re all a bunch of history geeks on a weekend get-away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0747.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0747.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Stargazing.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The next day we did a lot of hiking and exploring with one of our really cool Bedouin guides. We were exhausted by the end of it all and were happy to eventually make it back to our van. As soon as we got home I collapsed on my bed and was out for the rest of the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0783.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0783.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our hiking guide.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0750.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0750.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our campsite during the peaceful hours of the morning.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0934.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0934.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Camel adventures.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Reading abroad</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/reading-abroad/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 18:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/reading-abroad/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Time stops for no one. Almost three of our six weeks here are now gone, which means soon we’ll be rotating sites so next week I’ll start working with Dr. Johnson in his beloved tomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s strange how quick we are to become used to daily experiences—no matter how amazing they are—and to begin to take them for granted without even noticing. Sometimes I catch myself speeding through everything without taking the time to marvel again at the beauty in the sights, sounds, and smells that surround me. That’s when I force myself to stop whatever I’m doing and take it all in once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0064.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0064.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;From within the triclinium, on the processional way to Petra&amp;#39;s famous high place.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I discovered the perfect reading spot—or rather it was shown to me by one of our team members. The rooftop of our building has a breathtaking view of the whole region. From there I can see most of Petra, the villagers of Umm Sayhoon, and the lights and buildings of Wadi Musa. Though I only recently realized how great of a reading spot it is, it’s the perfect time to start my new book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0088.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0088.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The view from our rooftop on a cloudy day. Umm Sayhoon, our Bedouin village.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had more free time for fun reads here than I usually do during the school year. Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just that I find myself wanting so badly to better understand this desert world that I make the time to read more about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished reading &lt;em&gt;Married to a Bedouin&lt;/em&gt; recently, written by Marguerite van Geldermalsen, an adventurous New Zealander. It’s the story of her experiences meeting and falling in love with a Bedouin of Petra, marrying him and moving into his cave, joining the community, raising her children here, and many other experiences that largely ended with the death of her husband. Since then she’s moved back and forth a few times between the western world and Jordan. Though her writing is not exactly the best, her story is so captivating, and the details of life so intriguing, that it was well worth the read. What interesting insights into the lives of the people I interact with on a daily basis here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0194.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0194.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started reading her book I’ve wanted to meet Marguerite (&lt;em&gt;Fatima&lt;/em&gt; is her Arabic name) to hear her talk about her unique experiences. I did get the chance to meet her once when she came into the convenience store where I was buying some water. We talked briefly. It felt strange to think of this woman as a celebrity, but that’s exactly how I saw her after having read most of her book. We may yet have the chance to hear her tell her story since our director has invited her to have dinner with us one of these days, which I sure hope actually happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0257.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0257.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The book I’ve now started to read is T. E. Lawrence’s &lt;em&gt;Seven Pillars of Wisdom&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve wanted to read it ever since watching &lt;em&gt;Lawrence of Arabia&lt;/em&gt; while in Jerusalem. I was able to buy a copy on the iBook store to read on my iPad, but the glare makes it hard to read on the rooftop. Besides, everywhere I go I get dirty and dusty and there’s always sand blowing in the air—all things that I thoroughly enjoy about being here, but not an environment conducive to carrying an iPad in a barely protective case. So after asking and searching and negotiating at a couple of local bookshops (the only two I’ve found even remotely close to here), I finally got a hold of a paperback copy to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0183.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0183.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;She always makes friends with the animals.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I also got a book of David Roberts&amp;rsquo; beautiful lithographs of Petra and the Holy Land, and a book titled &lt;em&gt;The Art of Jordan&lt;/em&gt;. The latter is an awesome reference book to understand the basics of the rich history of this country. I of course skipped right to the chapter on writing and language and read it thoroughly. I find myself strangely attracted to anything having to do with writing. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0234.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0234.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Life of an archaeologist</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/life-of-an-archaeologist/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 18:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/life-of-an-archaeologist/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I agreed to come on this trip, much of my enthusiasm came from the thought that I would get to learn about archaeology the very best way possible: by &lt;em&gt;becoming&lt;/em&gt; an archaeologist myself for six weeks. That initial excitement has slowly grown over the last year, accumulating more and more as I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared, until becoming an unstoppable avalanche of anticipation for what my adventures here would entail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I&amp;rsquo;m not an archaeology major, Ancient Near Eastern Studies owes a lot to archaeology. I&amp;rsquo;ve been called the &amp;ldquo;texts person&amp;rdquo; of the group, but I certainly recognize the necessary cooperation between the book and the shovel that both lead towards the same objective. Besides, every child dreams of being Indiana Jones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0343.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0343.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Some of our equipment and site directors riding up to Ad-Deir.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Our life here as archaeologists-in-training consists of the following. Every morning we wake up for an early breakfast, get ourselves and our equipment into the van, drive down the wadi to the center of Petra, load equipment unto our shoulders and a couple of donkeys, walk up nearly a thousand ancient steps to the Ad-Deir plateau, divide into excavation groups, dig dig dig, take measurements and record, collect artifacts, dig dig dig, take a break, dig dig dig. We then clean up, gather our equipment, walk back down the steps past Bedouin shops and tourists, get in the van, make it home by 2pm for lunch. Then it&amp;rsquo;s shower time and nap time, followed usually by pottery washing and diagnosis, sometimes a lecture, and dinner. It&amp;rsquo;s a rough life, but somebody&amp;rsquo;s got to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0369.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0369.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The sifting station for our lower trench.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Really, as physically demanding as it all is, I feel so blessed to be here. I&amp;rsquo;m quickly learning way more about pottery than I ever wanted to know, and the blisters on my hands certainly don&amp;rsquo;t feel very nice, but it is such a blast to be involved with the unearthing and re-discovery of the past. I&amp;rsquo;m finding that what makes me happiest here are some of the really small and simple things: The feeling of not caring how dirty I get, the cool breeze that feels so heavenly when the sun is up high, the languages I hear around me that I can understand like Spanish and Hebrew, the surprise of finding that my water is still cold as it rushes down my throat, the simple discovery of some especially beautiful piece of pottery while sifting through mounds of dirt, and so so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0376.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0376.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Initial digging at one of our trenches on the plateau.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Today I learned a lot of Bedouin Arabic as I chatted with one of our fellow Bedouin workers at the sifting station. All the workers call me &lt;em&gt;Swelem&lt;/em&gt;, which is the Arabic name they decided to give me. I&amp;rsquo;m also becoming so familiar with the way up to the plateau that I like to get ahead of the group and explore alternate routes a bit. Today I took the &amp;ldquo;grand processional way,&amp;rdquo; which includes climbing a wall that clearly becomes a waterfall when it decides to rain. The climb up the long stairs is beginning to feel like a walk in the park—I was offered a donkey ride up today but decided to walk most of the way because I actually enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If nothing else, I am positive that after this trip I will be in the best shape of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0353.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0353.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mid-day break time.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Break days</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/break-days/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 18:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/break-days/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our weekends here are essentially Friday and Saturday, since Sundays are normal workdays just like the rest of the week—heavy, heavy workdays. I&amp;rsquo;ll go more into what a typical workday as an archaeologist in the field is like some other time. Right now, I just want to talk about our break days this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0098.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0098.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Friday was our day to go exploring some castles in the area. After a little lecture on the Crusades and the forts the Crusaders built around here, we went out on our field trips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love being in a place where the definition of &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; is so different than what that word means in the states. At home, &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; refers to the 19th, 18th, and _rarely _the 17th centuries. At that point you&amp;rsquo;re practically delving into the realm of ancient. Here, however, anything after the 15th century is considered fairly modern. When you say something is &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; you&amp;rsquo;re at least talking about 1,500, 2,000, or 2,500 year-old structures and artifacts. Sometimes even much older than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0042.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0042.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Shobak Castle&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Crusader castles we visited Friday were the Kerak and the Shobak castles. They were lots of fun to explore. The Shobak castle I had visited with my Jerusalem group two years ago, and it was a little strange to enter rooms I distinctly remember taking pictures in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0274.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0274.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0297.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0297.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Showing off their newly purchased keffiyehs.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Saturday—our second break day—we spent at &amp;ldquo;Little Petra.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s basically a Nabataean complex that is much smaller but comparable to Petra in some ways. It also had plenty of tombs to visit and some breathtaking scenery. The blue of the sky that day made it all that much more beautiful. We visited a neolithic site on the way, which dates to around 10,000 BCE. Now that&amp;rsquo;s old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0231.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0231.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A tomb in Little Petra.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0245.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0245.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Petra, wonder of the world</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/petra-wonder-of-the-world/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 20:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/petra-wonder-of-the-world/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;It is absolutely unbelievable that I&amp;rsquo;m actually in this place. Not only that I’m here, but that I’m doing what I’m here to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came to Petra for the first time almost two years ago as part of the BYU Jerusalem Center study abroad. I remember the preparation we received prior to our Jordan trip, and how we were told that we would want to see as much of Petra as we possibly could during our single day here. Our professor put up a map of the city and outlined some of the major sites we would want to see. Nothing, however, could have prepared me for the grandeur of this ancient city of rock. I fell in love with it immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0444.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0444.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The exit to the siq, with an enticing glimpse of the famous Al-Khazneh.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For that reason I have been so anxious to return—to relive my first visit, only extended from a single day to a six-week excursion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, here I am. And not only do I get to visit it every day, come to know this city intimately, and help discover and preserve its wonderfully rich history, but I actually get to _live_ here. Not inside the city itself, mind you, but in a Bedouin village overlooking central Petra. Every morning I wake up to an incredible view of the ancient city, often to the music of the Muslim call to prayer that I find so beautiful. It&amp;rsquo;s all sometimes too much to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0647.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0647.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;My room with a view of Petra out the window.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-bedul-and-the-middle-east&#34;&gt;The Bedul and the Middle East&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These Bedouin, who form a tribe known as the Bedul, lived in Petra itself not long ago. They lived in the ancient caves and controlled the markets for souvenirs, donkey rides, and other tourist attractions that still line the streets. But after Petra became a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1985, the Jordanian government relocated the Bedul to Umm Sayhoun, a village adjacent to Wadi Musa. It’s this small village that will be my home for the next few weeks. Most of the Bedul I&amp;rsquo;ve met were born in the caves, but they&amp;rsquo;re now building their lives here. They still go down to Petra each day and make their living off of tourism, but are no longer allowed to live in the Nabataean capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I also made some new Bedul friends. One of the students has been getting to know the women who cook our meals, and I’ve been telling her about how much I wish I could get to know them too. It can be difficult to become friends with the natives, particularly the women, because of strict cultural boundaries that I don’t fully understand and that I don’t want to overstep. But today while they were preparing lunch, I was invited to go talk to them! I spent a good hour and a half or so in the kitchen chatting and laughing with these wonderful women. They were very open about all sorts of things, including the old traditions that they love and the ones that they want to change. They explained how much things are changing, even among the Bedouin, as new generations arise that are educated, learn English, and have access to the knowledge of the world via the internet. I found it fascinating to see these women, in their beautiful, traditional, Bedouin dresses, pull out their phones and show me pictures from their Facebook accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0826.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0826.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A young Bedouin riding through Wadi Mataha.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There is something very special about this place. The Middle East has a very different feel than anywhere else I’ve been, and it’s a feel that I find strangely like—well—like &lt;em&gt;home&lt;/em&gt;. I love the warmth of the people, the smell of home-cooked meals full of spices, the children who seem so free—always playing out on the street, dirty, and happy as can be—and the vast landscapes of red desert, shrubs, and wild goats. I love the sense of family and community that is so strong in this part of the world. I love that a people so poor in material comforts and so aged by hardships that are clearly visible in each of their faces, are so quick to laugh and enjoy their moments together. I love the religious devotion, the love for God and his constant blessings, the love of prayer and fasting and scripture—things that bind them together and increase their love toward one other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;preparation-and-hard-work&#34;&gt;Preparation and hard work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we’ve only been preparing for our excavations by touring around the city, getting accustomed to our new home, and doing lots of readings and homework. But tomorrow we begin the hard work. Tomorrow we will actually be taking equipment up and beginning to set up our work areas. The group has been divided into two crews, one to begin work with Dr. Johnson in the tombs of Wadi Mataha, and the other to start with Dr. Finlayson on the Ad-Deir Plateau. I’ve been assigned to the Ad-Deir Plateau. In a few weeks we’ll rotate and get to work in the other area, which will allow us to experience two different ways of doing archaeology under two different site directors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0830.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0830.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The tomb on the right is the one we will be excavating under Dr. Johnson.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;What do I hope to get out of all this? Well there is certainly quite a bit that I expect to learn and experience. My expectations range from developing technical skills of archaeology, to understanding the history of the area better, to getting to know the modern people who live here today. You could say that for me it’s about the people—the ancient Edomites, Nabataeans, and Romans who once roamed this land, and the living, breathing Bedouin people, for whom Petra is their livelihood and home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a firm believer that there is so much to learn from all peoples and cultures, regardless of where, when, or how they live. And this is about the greatest opportunity I could ask for to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0605.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0605.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Paris is always a good idea</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/paris-is-always-a-good-idea/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 18:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/paris-is-always-a-good-idea/</guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;I never quite realized how much hard work a dedicated blogger must put into his or her posts and photos. This is especially true when traveling in areas where free internet is hard to come by. For me it has meant, more than anything, lack of sleep. Such as right now when I am up in my hotel room in Amman, running on my minimal sleep from the last few days, and unwilling to go to bed until at least something is published. But hey, I&amp;rsquo;ve just been to Paris and I want to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen and learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving in Paris, I was immediately thrown into the hecticness that is trying to figure out what to do in a country where they speak a foreign language. Fortunately, I took seven years of French in school (three years in middle school and four years in high school). Unfortunately, about 95% of my speaking ability is completely gone, and has been replaced by a frustrating habit of using Hebrew words when trying to speak French. Fortunately, I can still understand almost everything I read and a decent amount of what I hear. It&amp;rsquo;s sad how easy it is to forget a language that you never use. Perhaps one of the biggest things I got out of this trip was the deep desire to one day live in France for at least a few months and dedicate myself to learning (re-learning?) the beautiful French language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed at the &lt;a href=&#34;caulaincourt.com&#34;&gt;Caulaincourt Boutique Hostel&lt;/a&gt; in northern Paris. I loved the service of the staff and of my fellow young travelers. I decided on that hostel largely because it was one of the very few who had an all-male room. That certainly helped me feel more comfortable, and it even allowed me to have the room all to myself the first night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0170.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0170.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sure picked a great hostel.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see, fun experiences. I ran into the LDS Missionaries on the metro my first few hours in Paris and they helped me get to Notre Dame. They also showed me the chapel and visitors&amp;rsquo;  center close by. Had some amazing gillatto. Took a nap in the Louvre when I just could not take the jet lag anymore. Climbed the Eiffel Tower at night—twice. Walked around the gardens of Versailles while taking shelter from the rain. Witnessed a large demonstration marching towards the Palais Garnier, of Phantom of the Opera fame, and did my best to avoid the crowd. Had some incredible pastas, escargot, weird pizza thing, steak, and of course various cheeses and pastries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0038.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0038.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Notre Dame.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;One word of advice for anyone wanting to visit famous sites: always be aware of national holidays!! As it turns out, May 1st is one of those days when almost everything in Paris shuts down. As it so happened, that was the day I had planned to see _most _of the Louvre, as wells as the Orsay Museum. Luckily, an unplanned trip to the Louvre the day before allowed me to see some of the most famous paintings, including the Mona Lisa. Unfortunately, I was saving my most anticipated exhibit of the museum—the ancient near eastern artifacts—for May 1st. Seeing the sign at the entrance announcing the museum&amp;rsquo;s closure for the day was like taking punch to the gut and a slap to the face. I sure felt foolish. But I took comfort in the fact that I plan to return one day in the not-too-distant future. And hey, were it not for that I would have not seen many of the great sites I saw that day, such as Versailles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for my two Paris goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;have-a-full-conversation-on-the-street-with-a-french-person-in-french&#34;&gt;Have a full conversation on the street with a French person—in French.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I can confidently say that I had multiple conversations with French people in French. I mean, &amp;ldquo;excuse me where is the bathroom?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;over there on the left,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;thank you,&amp;rdquo; is a full conversation, no? Oui. But I&amp;rsquo;m afraid a truly engaging French conversation will have to wait until a future time when it takes me less than five minutes to think of the proper response to a simple question asked to me on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0029.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/dsc_0029.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Life in Paris.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;get-a-totally-epic-picture-in-front-of-the-eiffel-tower-and-send-it-to-someone-as-a-postcard&#34;&gt;Get a totally epic picture in front of the Eiffel Tower and send it to someone as a postcard.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The epic picture has been taken. Now I just have to send it as a postcard. Details forthcoming (once I find a place to print my picture).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>T-minus hours</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/t-minus-hours/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 08:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/t-minus-hours/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You know that feeling when you suddenly realize that maybe you should&amp;rsquo;ve just played it safe with a boring summer at home instead of being crazy enough to buy plane tickets that will take you all over the world? No? Good. Me neither.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I nervous? Sure. But the excitement of the prospect of fulfilling so many dreams in the next four short months far outweighs any other emotions going through me right now. It&amp;rsquo;s the anticipation that&amp;rsquo;s killing me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/screen-shot-2014-04-29-at-1-44-22-am.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/screen-shot-2014-04-29-at-1-44-22-am.png&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ahhhhh!!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In only a few hours I will be on a plane to the great French City of Light. Days later I will be on another plane to the rock-built capital of the ancient Nabataeans, and one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New7Wonders_of_the_World&#34;&gt;new seven wonders of the world&lt;/a&gt;. In about six weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll once again soar through the clouds (isn&amp;rsquo;t that miracle enough?), this time to go to the supposed birthplace of democracy, only to fly that same night to the Holy Land and take a bus to the City of David. Two weeks more and a different adventure begins at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Land_of_Hope_and_Glory&#34;&gt;land of hope and glory&lt;/a&gt;, as does my experience as a student at one of the oldest universities in the world. Afterwards comes some relaxing and hiking in the mountains once crossed by Hannibal and a bunch of unlucky elephants. And then, well, it&amp;rsquo;s back to the Rockies for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is sure to be one action-packed summer. I have a feeling I&amp;rsquo;ll come back from my &amp;ldquo;vacation&amp;rdquo; much more tired than how I left. But hey, that&amp;rsquo;s what adventures are for, right? At least that&amp;rsquo;s what I keep telling myself. You always come back needing a vacation from your vacation. The only brief moment of respite I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get have been a couple days of post-finals wind-down walks, bike rides, bonfires, sleep-ins, and laziness. And now the bags are (mostly) packed and I&amp;rsquo;m ready to get this thing underway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/dsc_0016.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/dsc_0016.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Recent mountain biking expedition.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that a list of what I want to get out of all this would help me actually achieve it! So here it is, the (initial) goal list for Juan&amp;rsquo;s Summer 2014 Adventures (subject to change):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have a full conversation on the street with a French person—in French.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a totally epic picture in front of the Eiffel Tower and send it to someone as a postcard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find a human skeleton in Petra.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take a picture on the pinnacle of Ad Deir in Petra. (Only if we&amp;rsquo;re allowed up there of course.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find a way to make it to the acropolis in Athens to see the Parthenon with what little time I have there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advance a full level of Hebrew (to ד) during my two weeks in Jerusalem!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have a meal at the BYU Jerusalem Center with friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do a morning jog up Mount Scopus at least five times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write a killer research paper through my Cambridge PKP Supervision Option.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Win the Kennedy Center ISP Blog Competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take three worthy pictures to submit to the annual ISP Photo Contest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Visit a castle in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wear a kilt in public.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Punt down the River Cam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to a King&amp;rsquo;s Singers performance in King&amp;rsquo;s College Chapel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hike to the top of Schilthorn in the Alps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make it back to Provo in one piece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list is sure to grow as I come up with more ideas that sound awesome, and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably post it as its own page where I will keep track of the goals I accomplish. &lt;strong&gt;Do you have any suggestions for things to add to the list?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2014-04-14-17-28-09.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2014-04-14-17-28-09.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Frijoles Pinto, anyone?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Dead Sea Scrolls and Moab</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/dead-sea-scrolls-and-moab/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 02:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/dead-sea-scrolls-and-moab/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Classes are now over for the semester, and I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be getting ready for finals. Yet it (unsurprisingly) wasn&amp;rsquo;t hard to convince myself that writing a blog post is almost as important as studying. Reading days are for relaxing after all—right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how did I decide to spend the last weekend before the end of classes? A legitimate question indeed. Well I received an email last week asking for someone willing to help out at the Dead Sea Scrolls Conference at the Leonardo Museum in Salt Lake City over the weekend. I was already hoping to make it up for the conference, so helping out with it was an unanticipated perk. Along with that opportunity I was also asked to take Dr. Emanuel Tov—former Editor-in-Chief of the international Dead Sea Scrolls Publication Project—up from Provo. The car ride up with Dr. Tov and my friend Justin was great. Probably the best part of it all was trying out my modern Hebrew and understanding everything he said!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2014-04-11-13-07-24-1.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2014-04-11-13-07-24-1.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Manning the front table at the DSS Conference!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The conference was a blast to be involved with, and I got the chance to meet some of the most influential Dead Sea Scrolls scholars in the world. What a privilege!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2014-04-11-20-12-04.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2014-04-11-20-12-04.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/students.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/students.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Various students, faculty, and special guests mingling.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;While at the conference I received a call from a friend asking if I wanted to go down to Moab that night and spend the weekend there. As Moab is one of those places I have always dreamt of visiting—and which for whatever reason I&amp;rsquo;m never able to make it to—my response in the affirmative burst from my mouth without hesitation. On my way home after the conference I stopped at Best Buy to purchase my much anticipated Nikon D3200. I was already planning on buying it (after &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; research, of course) and figured the Moab trip would be a perfect opportunity to get familiar with it before taking it around the world this summer. How right I was!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2014-04-12-12-46-17.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2014-04-12-12-46-17.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Monticello LDS Temple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Moab was absolutely mesmerizing. We began our trip Saturday morning at 1:00am, made it to Price where we decided to sleep in the car for a couple of hours, attended the temple in Monticello, went through part of Canyonlands, and then entered Arches National Park. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but take pictures all throughout the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hike up to Delicate Arch was the highlight of the trip. The weather was a perfect balance of sunlight and cool breeze. The scenery was everything I&amp;rsquo;d imagined, and the arch was quite the sight to behold. At times it felt somewhat like a spiritual journey—connecting with nature, enjoying the beauty of God&amp;rsquo;s creations. These pictures can&amp;rsquo;t possibly do it justice. Pictures are never the same as the real thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=&amp;ldquo;rectangular&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;55,56,57,58,59,60,61,62,63,64,65,66,67&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Adventure is out there</title>
        <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/adventure-is-out-there/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 20:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Juan Pinto</author>
        <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/adventure-is-out-there/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the ramblings of a simple man, with a simple life, but who dreams big and is not afraid to try new things. I decided that I needed a place to post all of my present and future adventures, and thus you are now seeing the result of that idea. Why the awkward blog name, you ask? I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that for you to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without giving my life story, here is all the background information you may want to know (or not): I was born in Cali, Colombia, where I grew up until I was eight. At that point my family moved to New Jersey, where they&amp;rsquo;re still living. I served a two-year proselyting mission for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mormon.org&#34;&gt;The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints&lt;/a&gt; in Las Vegas, Nevada, which changed my life. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying Ancient Near Eastern Studies at Brigham Young University, and like to consider myself an aspiring Hebrew scholar. Yes, I am very much a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wikihow.com/Tell-the-Difference-Between-Nerds-and-Geeks&#34;&gt;geek&lt;/a&gt;—and proud of it. But don&amp;rsquo;t let that fool you. I dream of traveling the world and meeting people from very different backgrounds, as my summer plans below will attest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/summer2014travels.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/summer2014travels.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My plans for this summer began as an unexpected invitation to participate in an archaeological excavation at one of my favorite places in the world: Petra, Jordan. From there things quickly escalated, and my current plans are as follows: Paris, Petra, Athens, Jerusalem, Cambridge (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pem.cam.ac.uk/international-programmes/summer-programmes/pembroke-kings-programme/&#34;&gt;PKP Study Abroad&lt;/a&gt;), and possibly Switzerland. I am blessed enough to have some very generous sources of funding for some of my adventures. In fact, if you follow me along for the ride, you will soon see that I am constantly blessed so much more than I deserve. But not just me—&lt;a href=&#34;http://thedailymiracle.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;daily miracles&lt;/a&gt; are out there for anyone willing to see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/jerusalemcenter-6-25-2012-2-40-44-pm.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jdpinto.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/jerusalemcenter-6-25-2012-2-40-44-pm.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 80%;&#34; class=&#34;align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;In front of the Treasury in Petra. Summer 2012&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Before my travels begin however, and I do hope you join me for at least some of them, I still have the rest of this semester to get through. Not to drudge through, mind you—only to get through joyfully.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
