<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jordan on internet weblog</title>
    <link>https://juandpinto.com/tags/jordan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jordan on internet weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://juandpinto.com/tags/jordan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan training and thoughts on education</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jordan-training-and-thoughts-on-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jordan-training-and-thoughts-on-education/</guid>
      <description>I spent most of last week at a Fulbright training in Amman, Jordan. All the Fulbright English Teaching Assistants from the entire MENA region (Middle East, North Africa) were brought there for an intense few days of training on language acquisition theories, teaching techniques, and lesson planning. And intense it was!
    We had three entire days of trainings, discussions, workshops, and even mock classes that we planned and then presented to the rest of the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrapping-up Petra</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 21:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</guid>
      <description>In only a few hours I am to get on a plane and begin the next phase of my adventures this summer. The last six weeks have blown by much faster than I can believe. But, c&amp;rsquo;est la vie I suppose.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really have much to say at this point, though maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just because I&amp;rsquo;m so tired. We spent the day driving to Amman and relaxing in our hotel rooms, but though my body is exhausted, my mind is too excited to sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient scrivenings, living tongues</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/ancient-scrivenings-living-tongues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 22:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/ancient-scrivenings-living-tongues/</guid>
      <description>I spent over half an hour yesterday speaking Hebrew with a native Israeli over Skype. It was an oral evaluation as part of the preparations for my two-week intensive ulpan which begins this coming Sunday! I had forgotten just how much I love that language until I got to listen to it again and speak it with surprising ease. I spent an hour after that just relaxing to Hebrew music and loving it all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of tombs and skeletons</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/of-tombs-and-skeletons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 21:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/of-tombs-and-skeletons/</guid>
      <description>This week I relocated from working at the temple on the mountaintop to the tomb in the valley. It&amp;rsquo;s my official transition to the second and last part of my adventure as an archaeologist this summer. Having been here for three of the six weeks meant it was time to rotate crews and excavation sites, so I am now working under a different site director in a very different place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desert get-away</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/desert-get-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 18:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/desert-get-away/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever seen _Lawrence of Arabia_ then you know all about the incredible beauty that can be found in the deserts of the Arab world. One such beautiful place, Wadi Rum, was the location for most of the filming of the movie, and this weekend I got to hike and camp out in that very place.
We were told about the chance to go to Wadi Rum while we were still in the States, preparing for our trip, and of course I could not possibly pass up the chance of something like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading abroad</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/reading-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 18:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/reading-abroad/</guid>
      <description>Time stops for no one. Almost three of our six weeks here are now gone, which means soon we’ll be rotating sites so next week I’ll start working with Dr. Johnson in his beloved tomb.
It’s strange how quick we are to become used to daily experiences—no matter how amazing they are—and to begin to take them for granted without even noticing. Sometimes I catch myself speeding through everything without taking the time to marvel again at the beauty in the sights, sounds, and smells that surround me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life of an archaeologist</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/life-of-an-archaeologist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 18:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/life-of-an-archaeologist/</guid>
      <description>When I agreed to come on this trip, much of my enthusiasm came from the thought that I would get to learn about archaeology the very best way possible: by becoming an archaeologist myself for six weeks. That initial excitement has slowly grown over the last year, accumulating more and more as I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared, until becoming an unstoppable avalanche of anticipation for what my adventures here would entail.
Though I&amp;rsquo;m not an archaeology major, Ancient Near Eastern Studies owes a lot to archaeology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break days</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/break-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 18:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/break-days/</guid>
      <description>Our weekends here are essentially Friday and Saturday, since Sundays are normal workdays just like the rest of the week—heavy, heavy workdays. I&amp;rsquo;ll go more into what a typical workday as an archaeologist in the field is like some other time. Right now, I just want to talk about our break days this week.
    Friday was our day to go exploring some castles in the area. After a little lecture on the Crusades and the forts the Crusaders built around here, we went out on our field trips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petra, wonder of the world</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/petra-wonder-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 20:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/petra-wonder-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>It is absolutely unbelievable that I&amp;rsquo;m actually in this place. Not only that I’m here, but that I’m doing what I’m here to do.
I came to Petra for the first time almost two years ago as part of the BYU Jerusalem Center study abroad. I remember the preparation we received prior to our Jordan trip, and how we were told that we would want to see as much of Petra as we possibly could during our single day here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>