<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photography on internet weblog</title>
    <link>https://juandpinto.com/tags/photography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photography on internet weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 21:10:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://juandpinto.com/tags/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A bittersweet farewell</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/a-bittersweet-farewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 21:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/a-bittersweet-farewell/</guid>
      <description>Now that my Cambridge experience has come to an end, it&amp;rsquo;s time to reflect on my two months spent there. But first, a quick recap of my adventures of the last week.
Northern England I spent Tuesday through Thursday morning way up north. Some future in-laws have been living up there for the last two years, and they welcomed me with open arms. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to expect—not being familiar with the towns and sights to see up there—but wanted to go up anyway to spend time with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The final stretch</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/the-final-stretch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 22:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/the-final-stretch/</guid>
      <description>With less than a week to go here at Cambridge, I’m definitely feeling the pressure to do some of the things I still haven’t gotten around to. That has so far meant a few days of traveling and visiting some of the most beautiful areas of Cambridge.
I was also informed yesterday that I won the “Academic Life” category of the PKP Photo Competition! That does mean I get a prize, though I have yet to find out what it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Hogwarts</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/welcome-to-hogwarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 22:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/welcome-to-hogwarts/</guid>
      <description>My first week at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry has been a tremendous success. I&amp;rsquo;ve got the _wingardium leviosa _spell down pretty well, and have almost mastered the expelliarmus spell. Next up: avada kedavra.
But in all seriousness. This place is awesome.
  Feeling fancy at King&amp;#39;s Dining Hall.    Across the River Cam, King&amp;#39;s College.  My arrival at Cambridge—the town—was uneventful. I took the train from Stansted Airport and made it in about an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrapping-up Petra</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 21:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</guid>
      <description>In only a few hours I am to get on a plane and begin the next phase of my adventures this summer. The last six weeks have blown by much faster than I can believe. But, c&amp;rsquo;est la vie I suppose.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really have much to say at this point, though maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just because I&amp;rsquo;m so tired. We spent the day driving to Amman and relaxing in our hotel rooms, but though my body is exhausted, my mind is too excited to sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desert get-away</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/desert-get-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 18:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/desert-get-away/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever seen _Lawrence of Arabia_ then you know all about the incredible beauty that can be found in the deserts of the Arab world. One such beautiful place, Wadi Rum, was the location for most of the filming of the movie, and this weekend I got to hike and camp out in that very place.
We were told about the chance to go to Wadi Rum while we were still in the States, preparing for our trip, and of course I could not possibly pass up the chance of something like that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>