<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on internet weblog</title>
    <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on internet weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://juandpinto.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan training and thoughts on education</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jordan-training-and-thoughts-on-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jordan-training-and-thoughts-on-education/</guid>
      <description>I spent most of last week at a Fulbright training in Amman, Jordan. All the Fulbright English Teaching Assistants from the entire MENA region (Middle East, North Africa) were brought there for an intense few days of training on language acquisition theories, teaching techniques, and lesson planning. And intense it was!
    We had three entire days of trainings, discussions, workshops, and even mock classes that we planned and then presented to the rest of the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan for site and blog</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/plan-for-site-and-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 17:11:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/plan-for-site-and-blog/</guid>
      <description>This site is very much a work in progress. I have many IndieWeb protocols I hope to implement in the near future, especially WebMentions. I also want to import many of my past ramblings from my previous blog (last used in 2014!) and maybe even from Facebook and Twitter.
Still, I think it important to give a basic overview of what I plan to do here. This post will address two questions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation for renewed blog</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/motivation-for-renewed-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/motivation-for-renewed-blog/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot lately about the internet presence I wish to create for myself. With all of this year&amp;rsquo;s revelations on Facebook&amp;rsquo;s serious data mismanagement (Cambridge Analytica), political interference (Russian hackers), failure to control hate speech (Myanmar genocide), and—most recently—dishonest efforts to shift blame (oh boy, where to begin), the backlash against social media platforms as a whole has reached fever pitch. It has caused me to reflect on my own contributions to the direction the web takes and our legacy for future generations of internauts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigotry and fear: The chicken and the egg</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/bigotry-and-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/bigotry-and-fear/</guid>
      <description>Lately, the world has seemed caught in the intoxicating mentality of us versus them. There’s nothing new about this. Yet the ongoing Syrian refugee crisis has proven a worthy litmus test for the way we experience life. Are these people victims of tragedy or Islamic instigators of terrorism? Do we aid the oppressed or protect our children?
Mark Twain once suggested that “travel is fatal to prejudice, bigotry, and narrow-mindedness.”￼ Yes, my dear man, well said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stowaway Magazine: Petra&#39;s Hidden Treasures</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/stowaway-magazine-petras-hidden-treasures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/stowaway-magazine-petras-hidden-treasures/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed by the great Natalie Campbell for this wonderful article published on Stowaway Magazine. It describes some of the highlights of my time excavating in Petra last summer. Natalie also does a good job capturing a snapshot of what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be a student archaeologist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bittersweet farewell</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/a-bittersweet-farewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 21:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/a-bittersweet-farewell/</guid>
      <description>Now that my Cambridge experience has come to an end, it&amp;rsquo;s time to reflect on my two months spent there. But first, a quick recap of my adventures of the last week.
Northern England I spent Tuesday through Thursday morning way up north. Some future in-laws have been living up there for the last two years, and they welcomed me with open arms. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to expect—not being familiar with the towns and sights to see up there—but wanted to go up anyway to spend time with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The final stretch</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/the-final-stretch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 22:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/the-final-stretch/</guid>
      <description>With less than a week to go here at Cambridge, I’m definitely feeling the pressure to do some of the things I still haven’t gotten around to. That has so far meant a few days of traveling and visiting some of the most beautiful areas of Cambridge.
I was also informed yesterday that I won the “Academic Life” category of the PKP Photo Competition! That does mean I get a prize, though I have yet to find out what it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge and beyond</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/cambridge-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 21:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/cambridge-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>Wow, where to even begin? It&amp;rsquo;s now been just over a month since my last entry, which means I essentially have only two more weeks here at Cambridge. And believe me when I say that what an adventure it has been!
  Inside King&amp;#39;s College, Cambridge. AKA home.  As a bit of background, our time here is split into two halves called modules. My module 1 consisted of constant classes, readings, homework, and papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Hogwarts</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/welcome-to-hogwarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 22:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/welcome-to-hogwarts/</guid>
      <description>My first week at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry has been a tremendous success. I&amp;rsquo;ve got the _wingardium leviosa _spell down pretty well, and have almost mastered the expelliarmus spell. Next up: avada kedavra.
But in all seriousness. This place is awesome.
  Feeling fancy at King&amp;#39;s Dining Hall.    Across the River Cam, King&amp;#39;s College.  My arrival at Cambridge—the town—was uneventful. I took the train from Stansted Airport and made it in about an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jerusalem of gold</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jerusalem-of-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 21:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jerusalem-of-gold/</guid>
      <description>My second week in Jerusalem was one heck of an adventure. For the most part, it was a continuation of the awesomeness that had been my first week. But in some ways, things were very different.
  The Dome of the Rock and the Western Wall.    Worshippers at the Western Wall.  I decided that I needed to get out of the city at least once, so I chose to join a group from the hostel that was going down to the Judean Desert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journeys across the Mediterranean</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/journeys-across-the-mediterranean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 18:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/journeys-across-the-mediterranean/</guid>
      <description>After practically living _in _Petra for a month and a half, intimately getting to know the sites daily and being constantly surrounded by 2,000 year-old buildings and inscriptions, I thought seeing Athens and then Jerusalem wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make much of an impact on me. Boy was I wrong.
  Excited? Better believe it.  My day in Athens was a blast. I essentially just had an 11-hour layover, which was the perfect amount of time to visit the Acropolis and then the Acropolis Museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrapping-up Petra</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 21:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/wrapping-up-petra/</guid>
      <description>In only a few hours I am to get on a plane and begin the next phase of my adventures this summer. The last six weeks have blown by much faster than I can believe. But, c&amp;rsquo;est la vie I suppose.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really have much to say at this point, though maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just because I&amp;rsquo;m so tired. We spent the day driving to Amman and relaxing in our hotel rooms, but though my body is exhausted, my mind is too excited to sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient scrivenings, living tongues</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/ancient-scrivenings-living-tongues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 22:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/ancient-scrivenings-living-tongues/</guid>
      <description>I spent over half an hour yesterday speaking Hebrew with a native Israeli over Skype. It was an oral evaluation as part of the preparations for my two-week intensive ulpan which begins this coming Sunday! I had forgotten just how much I love that language until I got to listen to it again and speak it with surprising ease. I spent an hour after that just relaxing to Hebrew music and loving it all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of tombs and skeletons</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/of-tombs-and-skeletons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 21:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/of-tombs-and-skeletons/</guid>
      <description>This week I relocated from working at the temple on the mountaintop to the tomb in the valley. It&amp;rsquo;s my official transition to the second and last part of my adventure as an archaeologist this summer. Having been here for three of the six weeks meant it was time to rotate crews and excavation sites, so I am now working under a different site director in a very different place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desert get-away</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/desert-get-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 18:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/desert-get-away/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever seen _Lawrence of Arabia_ then you know all about the incredible beauty that can be found in the deserts of the Arab world. One such beautiful place, Wadi Rum, was the location for most of the filming of the movie, and this weekend I got to hike and camp out in that very place.
We were told about the chance to go to Wadi Rum while we were still in the States, preparing for our trip, and of course I could not possibly pass up the chance of something like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading abroad</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/reading-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 18:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/reading-abroad/</guid>
      <description>Time stops for no one. Almost three of our six weeks here are now gone, which means soon we’ll be rotating sites so next week I’ll start working with Dr. Johnson in his beloved tomb.
It’s strange how quick we are to become used to daily experiences—no matter how amazing they are—and to begin to take them for granted without even noticing. Sometimes I catch myself speeding through everything without taking the time to marvel again at the beauty in the sights, sounds, and smells that surround me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life of an archaeologist</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/life-of-an-archaeologist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 18:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/life-of-an-archaeologist/</guid>
      <description>When I agreed to come on this trip, much of my enthusiasm came from the thought that I would get to learn about archaeology the very best way possible: by becoming an archaeologist myself for six weeks. That initial excitement has slowly grown over the last year, accumulating more and more as I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared, until becoming an unstoppable avalanche of anticipation for what my adventures here would entail.
Though I&amp;rsquo;m not an archaeology major, Ancient Near Eastern Studies owes a lot to archaeology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break days</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/break-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 18:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/break-days/</guid>
      <description>Our weekends here are essentially Friday and Saturday, since Sundays are normal workdays just like the rest of the week—heavy, heavy workdays. I&amp;rsquo;ll go more into what a typical workday as an archaeologist in the field is like some other time. Right now, I just want to talk about our break days this week.
    Friday was our day to go exploring some castles in the area. After a little lecture on the Crusades and the forts the Crusaders built around here, we went out on our field trips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petra, wonder of the world</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/petra-wonder-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 20:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/petra-wonder-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>It is absolutely unbelievable that I&amp;rsquo;m actually in this place. Not only that I’m here, but that I’m doing what I’m here to do.
I came to Petra for the first time almost two years ago as part of the BYU Jerusalem Center study abroad. I remember the preparation we received prior to our Jordan trip, and how we were told that we would want to see as much of Petra as we possibly could during our single day here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris is always a good idea</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/paris-is-always-a-good-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 18:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/paris-is-always-a-good-idea/</guid>
      <description>I never quite realized how much hard work a dedicated blogger must put into his or her posts and photos. This is especially true when traveling in areas where free internet is hard to come by. For me it has meant, more than anything, lack of sleep. Such as right now when I am up in my hotel room in Amman, running on my minimal sleep from the last few days, and unwilling to go to bed until at least something is published.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-minus hours</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/t-minus-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 08:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/t-minus-hours/</guid>
      <description>You know that feeling when you suddenly realize that maybe you should&amp;rsquo;ve just played it safe with a boring summer at home instead of being crazy enough to buy plane tickets that will take you all over the world? No? Good. Me neither.
Am I nervous? Sure. But the excitement of the prospect of fulfilling so many dreams in the next four short months far outweighs any other emotions going through me right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Sea Scrolls and Moab</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/dead-sea-scrolls-and-moab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 02:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/dead-sea-scrolls-and-moab/</guid>
      <description>Classes are now over for the semester, and I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be getting ready for finals. Yet it (unsurprisingly) wasn&amp;rsquo;t hard to convince myself that writing a blog post is almost as important as studying. Reading days are for relaxing after all—right?
So how did I decide to spend the last weekend before the end of classes? A legitimate question indeed. Well I received an email last week asking for someone willing to help out at the Dead Sea Scrolls Conference at the Leonardo Museum in Salt Lake City over the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventure is out there</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/adventure-is-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 20:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/adventure-is-out-there/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the ramblings of a simple man, with a simple life, but who dreams big and is not afraid to try new things. I decided that I needed a place to post all of my present and future adventures, and thus you are now seeing the result of that idea. Why the awkward blog name, you ask? I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that for you to figure out.
Without giving my life story, here is all the background information you may want to know (or not): I was born in Cali, Colombia, where I grew up until I was eight.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>