<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cambridge on internet weblog</title>
    <link>https://juandpinto.com/tags/cambridge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cambridge on internet weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 21:10:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://juandpinto.com/tags/cambridge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A bittersweet farewell</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/a-bittersweet-farewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 21:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/a-bittersweet-farewell/</guid>
      <description>Now that my Cambridge experience has come to an end, it&amp;rsquo;s time to reflect on my two months spent there. But first, a quick recap of my adventures of the last week.
Northern England I spent Tuesday through Thursday morning way up north. Some future in-laws have been living up there for the last two years, and they welcomed me with open arms. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to expect—not being familiar with the towns and sights to see up there—but wanted to go up anyway to spend time with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The final stretch</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/the-final-stretch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 22:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/the-final-stretch/</guid>
      <description>With less than a week to go here at Cambridge, I’m definitely feeling the pressure to do some of the things I still haven’t gotten around to. That has so far meant a few days of traveling and visiting some of the most beautiful areas of Cambridge.
I was also informed yesterday that I won the “Academic Life” category of the PKP Photo Competition! That does mean I get a prize, though I have yet to find out what it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge and beyond</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/cambridge-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 21:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/cambridge-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>Wow, where to even begin? It&amp;rsquo;s now been just over a month since my last entry, which means I essentially have only two more weeks here at Cambridge. And believe me when I say that what an adventure it has been!
  Inside King&amp;#39;s College, Cambridge. AKA home.  As a bit of background, our time here is split into two halves called modules. My module 1 consisted of constant classes, readings, homework, and papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Hogwarts</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/welcome-to-hogwarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 22:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/welcome-to-hogwarts/</guid>
      <description>My first week at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry has been a tremendous success. I&amp;rsquo;ve got the _wingardium leviosa _spell down pretty well, and have almost mastered the expelliarmus spell. Next up: avada kedavra.
But in all seriousness. This place is awesome.
  Feeling fancy at King&amp;#39;s Dining Hall.    Across the River Cam, King&amp;#39;s College.  My arrival at Cambridge—the town—was uneventful. I took the train from Stansted Airport and made it in about an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jerusalem of gold</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jerusalem-of-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 21:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jerusalem-of-gold/</guid>
      <description>My second week in Jerusalem was one heck of an adventure. For the most part, it was a continuation of the awesomeness that had been my first week. But in some ways, things were very different.
  The Dome of the Rock and the Western Wall.    Worshippers at the Western Wall.  I decided that I needed to get out of the city at least once, so I chose to join a group from the hostel that was going down to the Judean Desert.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>