<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hebrew on internet weblog</title>
    <link>https://juandpinto.com/tags/hebrew/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hebrew on internet weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 21:57:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://juandpinto.com/tags/hebrew/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jerusalem of gold</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jerusalem-of-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 21:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/jerusalem-of-gold/</guid>
      <description>My second week in Jerusalem was one heck of an adventure. For the most part, it was a continuation of the awesomeness that had been my first week. But in some ways, things were very different.
  The Dome of the Rock and the Western Wall.    Worshippers at the Western Wall.  I decided that I needed to get out of the city at least once, so I chose to join a group from the hostel that was going down to the Judean Desert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journeys across the Mediterranean</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/journeys-across-the-mediterranean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 18:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/journeys-across-the-mediterranean/</guid>
      <description>After practically living _in _Petra for a month and a half, intimately getting to know the sites daily and being constantly surrounded by 2,000 year-old buildings and inscriptions, I thought seeing Athens and then Jerusalem wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make much of an impact on me. Boy was I wrong.
  Excited? Better believe it.  My day in Athens was a blast. I essentially just had an 11-hour layover, which was the perfect amount of time to visit the Acropolis and then the Acropolis Museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient scrivenings, living tongues</title>
      <link>https://juandpinto.com/blog/ancient-scrivenings-living-tongues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 22:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juandpinto.com/blog/ancient-scrivenings-living-tongues/</guid>
      <description>I spent over half an hour yesterday speaking Hebrew with a native Israeli over Skype. It was an oral evaluation as part of the preparations for my two-week intensive ulpan which begins this coming Sunday! I had forgotten just how much I love that language until I got to listen to it again and speak it with surprising ease. I spent an hour after that just relaxing to Hebrew music and loving it all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>